# KENNY JEAN // SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(561)670-5970 Address: West Palm Beach, FL♦ Email: Kennyjean561@gmail.com ♦Github: <a href="https://github.com/K-Tech19">https://github.com/K-Tech19</a> ♦ LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennyjean19/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennyjean19/</a> ♦ Portfolio: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennyjean19/">kennys-portfolio.netlify.app</a> ♦

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a Software developer who enjoys solving tough problems and breaking them down into easily programmable solutions. My previous job was in banking where I spent the last 5 years building trust with my clients and furthering my communication skills, which I am confident I can bring to any role.

## **SKILLS**

- LANGUAGES | JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, TypeScript
- LIBRARIES AND FRAMEWORK | React, Node.js, Express.js, Gatsby.js, Bootstrap
- DATABASE | PostgreSQL, SQL, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose
- OTHER | RESTful API, JSON, OOP, Heroku, Netlify

#### **PROJECTS**

## Rapid Connect 4 | HTML, CSS, JavaScript | GitHub

Merida, Mexico | 2-week duration

- Created a commercial representation of high speed connect where each player has 30 seconds to make a turn until one person is left standing.
- Completed project while overseas in Mexico.

#### Covid Tracker 2021 | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Chart.JS | GitHub

West Palm Beach, FL 1-week duration

- A React single page application that displays global up to date confirmed, recovered and deaths of individual countries during the pandemic.
- It uses an API that provides data of all reported cases depending on the specific country.
- Includes an accessibility dark mode when enabled gives the user an option to view the page in a more dark and less saturated color combination.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Podium Education | Instructor Associate**

Austin, Texas | May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Create and present lesson plans with the lead instructor to guide students in a live lecture session effectively.
- Grade student assignments to give meaningful feedback during Office hours.
- Familiarize oneself with different coding technologies to troubleshoot students issues.
- Assist students with industries standard projects while leading them in study hall content

#### **General Assembly | Teachers Assistant**

New York, New York | June 2021 - Current

- Provide students with mentorship and feedback on past assignments.
- Assist lead instructors with lessons and administrative duties.
- Perform quality assurance, research, troubleshooting, and debugging students' homework over several technologies, including JavaScript, ReactJS, Restful API and SQL.

## Bank of America | Relationship Banker

Jupiter, Florida | Sept 2019 - Dec 2020

- Built relationships over time to gain in depth knowledge of clients' financial life priorities and effectively positioning additional Bank of America products and services.
- Deepened client relationships with over 50+ customers per week via in-person conversation and referrals to our team specialists.
- Kept the workspace environmentally green by reducing daily paper usage, daily cash handling audits of all cash registers and merchandising abilities.

#### Cash America Pawn | Pawn Broker

Tallahassee, Florida | Jun 2018 - May 2020

- Complied with local, state and federal laws, including reviewing identification, obtaining thumbprint and verifying serial numbers against law enforcement databases.
- Handle cash and negotiable items in accordance with established policies and procedures.
- Inventory control, cash handling and merchandising abilities.

## **EDUCATION**

## General Assembly

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineer Immersive Miami, FL | Mar 2021

#### Florida Agricultural & Mechanical University

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration Tallahassee, FL | May 2019

#### Florida International University

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration Miami, FL | May 2016

## Palm Beach State College

Associate of Arts, Business Administration Palm Beach, FL | Dec 2014

### **Affiliations**

Iota Phi Theta Fraternity Incorporated | Initiate / Treasurer | Spring 2018-2019
Iota Phi Theta Fraternity Incorporated | Intake Coordinator | Spring 2019